<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<changelog name="Segue ChangeLog">
		<version number="1.0.7" date="future">
		<change author='adam'>
			The user full name, email, and type in the db are now updated from LDAP
			or other auth method if the db version doesn't match.
		</change>
	</version>
	<version number="1.0.6" date="2003-12-29">
		<fix author='adam' ref='750109' reftype='bug'>
			Now doesn't attempt to perform operations on nonexistant LDAP results.
		</fix>
		<fix author='gabe' ref='865065' reftype='bug'>
			Now checks that the destination name is not the same as the source name
			and is also not an empty string.
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="1.0.5" date="2003-12-19">
		<change author='adam'>
			LDAP authentication has been generalized and should now work with 
			most LDAP servers.
		</change>
		<change author='alex'>
			Refined admin tools UI.  Added all Segue users
			to add/edit user UI and allowed for searching by auth and user type.  Added
			pagination to add/edit slots UI and refined layout of search results
		</change>
		<fix author='alex' ref='853466' reftype='bug'>
			Classes now show up if the user is an admin.
		</fix>
		<fix author='alex' ref='853497' reftype='bug'>
			Removed link to assessments on default.inc.php
		</fix>
		<fix author='alex' ref='853501' reftype='bug'>
			Fixed a bug in add/edit classes UI so that classes existing classes 
			can now be edit.
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="1.0.4" date="2003-11-13">
		<fix author='adam'>
			Fixed a bug in the 1.0.3 permissions checking that prevented 
			institution users from accessing sites.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam'>
			Fixed a bug in fetching of sites where a user is editor, so that a
			database connection is guaranteed.
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="1.0.3" date="2003-11-12">
		<change author='dobo'>
			Default page and permissions checking re-written to be faster.
		</change>
		<change author='adam'>
			Permissions window now has Save/Cancel buttons at the top of the 
			window.
		</change>
		<important author='adam'>
			Segue expects that usernames are all lower-case. Checks are in place
			to force the creation of lowercase usernames when adding users, but 
			if you are using a custom authentication modules, these checks may 
			be bypassed and you should check that usernames in your user table 
			are lower-case if you see strange problems with permissions. 
		</important>
		<new author='adam'>
			Addition of an update framework for applying database updates in
			Segue. When templates/database updates are in a release, they
			will appear in the "Segue Updates" section of the "admin tools".
		</new>
		<change author='alex'>
			Two new site templates: "Advanced: Single Section" and 
			"Advanced: Blank".
		</change>
		<important author='adam'>
			New templates have been added. To create the new templates, log in 
			as an administrator, then go to 'admin tools' --> 'segue updates'
			and run the 1.0.3 update if needed.
		</important>
		<change author='alex'>
			Discussions now appear in-line instead of in a popup window.
		</change>
		<change author='alex'>
			Admin screens for users, classes, slots, and logs now have improved
			searching and pagination.
		</change>
		<fix author='gabe' ref='776452' reftype='bug'>
			Anonymous/Unauthenticated discussions are now working.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam' ref='809335' reftype='bug'>
			Class groups not listed from members
		</fix>
		<change author='adam' ref='804005' reftype='fr'>
			Editors of sections can now enable discussions for that section and
			select which (of the already availible editors) can post to it.
		</change>
		<fix author='adam' ref='803899' reftype='bug'>
			Co-Teaching profs now don't see site creation, grouping, or editing
			links if they are not the owner for a site. They see editing links
			as apropriate if they are editors.
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam' ref='803894' reftype='bug'>
			User's Full Names containing apostrophes now don't throw errors when
			adding to the user table.
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="1.0.2" date="2003-09-08">
		<change author='adam' ref='777065' reftype='fr'>
			The admin interface has been changed so that slot and their
			properties can be changed along side the classes and users. Custom 
			upload limits can be set in this slot interface now instead of
			editing the DB directly.
		</change>
		<fix author='adam' ref='802499' reftype='bug'>
			Story problems with the [De]Activate dates have been fixed
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam' ref='795587' reftype='bug'>
			Problems with the [De]Activate dates have been fixed
		</fix>
		<fix author='adam' ref='791954' reftype='bug'>
			The Move/Copy UI now shows the sitename to differentiate between
			similarly titled sites.
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="1.0.1" date="2003-08-08">
		<fix>
			Fixed the numerous bugs that were generated by the change below.
			(ouch)
		</fix>
		<change>
			Slots interface: administrators can now edit owner &amp; media
			library size for existing slots.
		</change>
		<fix author='adam' ref='784526' reftype='bug'>
			Fixed upload of PHP files bug.
		</fix>
		<important>
			DB CHANGE: The 'slot' table has a new column: 'slot_uploadlimit',
			which is an INT(10), corresponding to the number of bytes of the
			quota.
		</important>
		<new author='adam' ref='777065' reftype="fr">
			Media Library quota can be adjusted on a per-site basis through the
			slot database table. Add Slot interface upgraded too.
		</new>
		<fix author='gabe' ref='771969' reftype="bug">
			Upon logout, the session, instead of being completely destroyed,
			only unsets Segue-specific variables. The previous functionality was

			also killing other apps running under the same session.
		</fix>
	</version>
	<version number="1.0.0 rc1" date="2003-07-14">
		<new author='gabe'>
			Added new config option: $cfg[domain] -- the cookie domain for
			session info. Allows session info to cross sites if they are running

			the same instance of segue.
		</new>
		<new author='gabe'>
			Discussion links now displayed with statistics info.
		</new>
		<change author='gabe'>
			By-line for default page now has a link to a "credits" page with
			more info about the authors.
		</change>
		<change>
			ChangeLog is now held in XML format &amp; converted with XSL!
		</change>
		<change author='gabe'>
			"Powered by Segue" logo now takes you to the Segue page.
		</change>
	</version>
	<version number="1.0.0 beta1" date="2003-07-11">
		<change>
			Permissions can now be assigned to link type sections and pages and
			image and file type stories.
		</change>
		<fix>
			Headings and dividers are now properly displayed when not logged in.
		</fix>
		<important author="adam">
			DATABASE CHANGE! The class_number field in the class table should be
			changed in type from an int(11) to a varchar(15) and the default set

			to "000".
		</important>
		<fix author="gabe">
			When integrated with an LDAP server, Segue now correctly
			synchronizes the user and class database tables when adding 
			users/groups as editors who have not yet logged in/been added to the

			local tables.
		</fix>
		<change>
			Added Dobo Radichkov's name as a main editor on Segue websites &amp;
			program.
		</change>
		<change author="gabe">
			View/add slots interface: a used slot now displays a "-" under the
			delete column instead of non-linked "delete" text for clarity.
		</change>
	</version>
	<version number="1.0.0 alpha3" date="2003-06-08">
		<new author="adam">
			Owners of class sites can now easily add members of their class as
			an editor.
		</new>
		<change author="adam">
			Activation/Deactivation Date form now has valid day options.
		</change>
		<change author="adam">
			When an admin is acting as another person, they can only see what
			that person would see.
		</change>
		<fix author="gabe">
			The "default" page now appropriately shows sites of which a group
			member is owner.
		</fix>
		<fix author="adam">
			Move/Copy now shows sites properly when opened on first page load.
		</fix>
		<change>
			More debug output has been removed.
		</change>
	</version>
	<version number="1.0.0 alpha2" date="2003-06-07">
		<change author="gabe">
			Removed debug output.
		</change>
	</version>
	<version number="1.0.0 alpha" date="2003-06-06">
		<new>
			First official release.
		</new>
	</version>
	
	<authors>
		<name short="gabe">Gabe Schine</name>
		<name short="adam">Adam Franco</name>
		<name short="dobo">Dobo Radichkov</name>
		<name short="max">Max Ovsjanikov</name>
		<name short="alex">Alex Chapin</name>
	</authors>
	<reftypes>
		<reftype name="bug">565234</reftype>
		<reftype name="fr">565237</reftype>
	</reftypes>
	<groupid>82171</groupid>
</changelog>
